Aisling Foley

Senior Product Designer

I take complex problems and create simple solutions, balancing user needs and business objectives. Working in cross disciplinary teams, I take responsibility for all aspects of product design including strategy, research, testing and design.

hello@aisling-foley.com 07479552825 aisling-foley.com

Education

Scrum Product Owner (CSPO)

Georg Fasching

Jun 2018

Graphic Design /

Coláiste Stiofáin Naofa

2011 - 2012

BSC in Business Information Systems

University College Cork

2007 - 2011

Skills

Product strategy

User research

User testing

Visual design

Interaction design

Front end development

Delivery

Leadership

Experience

Potato / Senior Product Designer

Jan 2017 - Present | Product development agency

- Lead designer of a complex events product. I lead the redesign and creation of a design system. Alongside the implementation of collaborative ways of working, improving the teams health and effectiveness.
- Delivered a range of products collaborating with cross disciplinary teams and clients. Taking initial problems or opportunities, through to research, design, validation, build and refinement.
- Educated clients on agile ways of working. Highlighting the benefits of iterative, outcome rather than deliverable focused ways of working.
- Moonlighted as a product owner developed product strategies, created roadmaps and ensured the design and development teams were focused on the right thing.
- Design team hiring: including developing business cases for new hires, leading interviews and a redesign of the hiring process.

Furthermore / Product Designer

Oct 2016 - Dec 2016 | Product & service design agency

- Carried out competitor analysis & user research to develop a monetisation strategy for a health and wellness mobile app. Designed the associated product for creating and managing targeted in app advertising.
- Collaborated with the lead visual designer on an analytics product, advising on technical limitations and feasibility of design solutions, along with contributing to front end development on the product.
- Designed and launched the marketing site for the company's side product: a mobile app called Go Jauntly.

pebble (code) / Product Designer

Aug 2015 - Sep 2016 | Product development agency

- Worked in agile cross disciplinary teams, leading on product strategy, user research, visual design and front end development.
- Including: rapid product validation proof of concepts through to large scale complex internal tools.

Hoolux Medical / Lead UI/UX Designer

Jan 2014 - Jul 2015 | Health-tech/Advertising startup

- Lead the design and contributed to the front end development of the companies digital offerings to get them to market.
- Including: marketing site, analytics application, mobile application, tablet based platform to manage sign ups and email campaigns & their corresponding micro sites

Rocket Media / Designer & Front End Developer

Aug 2012 - Jan 2014 | Digital media agency

- Designed and contributed to the front end development of web applications for a range of clients.
- Including: bespoke responsive websites and point of sale, touch screen applications.